

RASHA RASHEED
Software Engineer

PROFILE

An experienced software engineer who is focused on ceaseless improvement, equipped for working under pressure, both as a project and people manager, talented in legitimate thinking and complying with time constraints.

Around four years of involvement in the software field has taught me a great deal about resilience, adaption and transformation.

Having gained invaluable experience in developing ERP applications, participated in all stages of SDLC and automation. I am driven by a fervent work ethic and genuine desire for self-improvement

Reach me at

rasharasheedr99@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/rasharasheed

CORE SKILLS

- C languages-C#,C++,C
- .Net
- WPF
- SQL
- XAML
- OOP Paradigm

BASE SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- Git
- Web API
- MVVM
- MVC
- ASP.Net

TOOLS

- Visual Studio
- SQL Server
- Jenkins
- Eclipse
- Aqua Studio
- Perforce

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sr. Associate Application Developer Sutherland Global Services Jun 2019 – Jun 2021 www.sutherlandglobal.com

- Client : <u>General Electrics</u>
 Project: <u>UView(Universal Viewer)</u> Automation
- Developed automation project with C# for healthcare application.
- Worked on deployment of the application with .NET framework and SQL database.
- Fixed bugs in the healthcare project used by radiologists.
- Majorly involved in supporting the backend for automation scenarios, test cases as per client requirement.
- Handled a total of 1500+ test cases, executed on Jenkins and reported through Application Lifecycle Management (ALM).
- Besides supporting automation framework, worked on installing/upgrading/troubleshooting the application environments.
- Participated and aware of all sorts of agile ceremonies and scrum methodologies.

Software Engineer Stimes Technologies

Dec 2016 - Oct 2018

- www.stimes.qa
- Project: Stimes ERP
- Developed windows based **ERP software** for clients over Qatar and UAE within an agile-driven team.
- Analysed system requirements and used systematic approaches to implement them on client delivery goals and project timeline constraints.
- Lead the team of 3, holding the responsibility of multiple domains including Payroll, Fleet, Real estate and Inventory.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Malayalam

PERSONAL INFORMATION



- Developed SQL packages and procedures based on functional requirements.
- Resolved customer issues by establishing workarounds and by fixing the code errors with in the .NET framework.
- Got my hands on WPF tools and functionalities for the software and customised client side RDLC reports as per requirements.
- Effectively served as sole administrator for many project units and versions and was awarded up on completion.

CERTIFICATIONS AND ACCOLADES

Best Performer of the Year

2017 - 2018

- Awarded by Stimes Technologies, Kerala, India.
- In recognition of my effort resulting in a high level of productivity and performance.

ASP.Net Training

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016

- Received advanced training in ASP.Net MVC and SQL Procedures for 3months from Integos Intelligent Solutions.
- Participated in design, brainstorming and code review sessions.

Node.Js WebDevelopment Workshop - Feb 2019

- A node.js web development workshop hosted by ping foundation under Govt. Cyberpark Kozhikode. (www.pingfoundation.org)
- I was one among the 30 tech enthusiasts volunteered with the mission of developing apps for social cause.
- I got to know more about HTML, CSS, bootstrap, node.js, mongo DB, git tool and to host a project on **github**.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science

-2016

Cochin University of Science And Technology, India